<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sebescudie</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on sebescudie</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>i also have a blog</title><link>/blog/first_post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/first_post/</guid><description>one day i might publish blog posts about development, computers and other things i enjoy. for now, there is just this dummy article.</description></item><item><title>Audi City Christmas 2016</title><link>/portfolio/audi-city/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/audi-city/</guid><description>In 2016, the Audi City store in Paris asked SUPERBIEN to turn its window into a mini advent-calendar. To do so, we equiped the window with a LIDAR and invited people to defrost it to reveal Audi&amp;rsquo;s cars.
As a back-end developer, I was in charge of gathering data from the LIDAR and creating the architecture of the application.
All the pictures below are provided by SUPERBIEN.
You can watch the full report here.</description></item><item><title>EDF Interactive Wall</title><link>/portfolio/edf-interactive-wall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/edf-interactive-wall/</guid><description>In 2016, SUPERBIEN was asked to create a giant touch senstive wall for EDF&amp;rsquo;s (national electricity company) booth at Viva Tech faire. The constrain for this project was to make the technology as invisible as possible.
To make the wall touch-sensitive, we hid capacitive sensors behind it to create interactive zones. This project was realy fun to work on since it also introduced lots of types of physical interactions with the wall.</description></item><item><title>Gamma Launcher</title><link>/portfolio/gammalauncher/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/gammalauncher/</guid><description>Gamma Launcher is a small GUI application (patched with vvvv gamma!) that allows you to start a specific vvvv version installed on your system, and add startup options such as -m (allow multiple instances) or --package-repositories (overrides your nugets with those from your development folder).
To get it, simply head over to the release section of the Github repo.</description></item><item><title>LIDAR App</title><link>/portfolio/lidar-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/lidar-app/</guid><description>At SUPERBIEN, I developed a stadalone application (codename LIDARApp) that allows to calibrate multiple SICK 2D LIDARs and perform blob-tracking with them.
To get a glimpse of what the application does, you can have a look at the recording of the 15th vvvv meetup where I made a quick demo of the app.
Right now, the app is being re-written to add more features and update it to the latest versions of vvvv and Elementa.</description></item><item><title>Oceans</title><link>/portfolio/oceans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/oceans/</guid><description>Ocean is a virtual immersive aqurium I worked on with SUPERBIEN. A total of 11 LIDARs made the 300 meters square video content interactive.
As a backend-developer, I was in charge of creating a standalone application that would allow to easily preview the data gathered by the LIDARs over the network, calibrate it (re-align the LIDARS on a 2D canvas) and perform blob-tracking on that set of data. This eventually gave birth to the LIDAR App on which you&amp;rsquo;ll have more information in a dedicated article.</description></item></channel></rss>