<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sebescudie</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on sebescudie</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MEMLABS - LAB02</title><link>/blog/memlab_02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/memlab_02/</guid><description>Encore un writeup, cette fois-ci sur le second lab du repo MEMLABS ! Sans plus attendre, la description du challenge :
One of the clients of our company, lost the access to his system due to an unknown error. He is supposedly a very popular &amp;ldquo;environmental&amp;rdquo; activist. As a part of the investigation, he told us that his go to applications are browsers, his password managers etc. We hope that you can dig into this memory dump and find his important stuff and give it back to us.</description></item><item><title>MEMLABS - LAB03</title><link>/blog/memlab_03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/memlab_03/</guid><description>Troisième post, troisième writeup MEMLABS ! Cette fois-ci je vais moins rentrer dans les détails de chaque commande. C&amp;rsquo;est parti pour la description du challenge :
A malicious script encrypted a very secret piece of information I had on my system. Can you recover the information for me please? Note-1: This challenge is composed of only 1 flag. The flag split into 2 parts. Note-2: You&amp;rsquo;ll need the first half of the flag to get the second.</description></item><item><title>MEMLABS - LAB01</title><link>/blog/memlab_01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/memlab_01/</guid><description>Premier article du blog, et c&amp;rsquo;est un writeup ! On va résoudre pas à pas le premier CTF du repo MEMLABS, qui propose de petits CTF centrés sur l&amp;rsquo;analyse de dumps mémoire.
Le but ici n&amp;rsquo;est pas de faire une introduction volatility, mais le writeup devrait être (je l&amp;rsquo;espère !) suffisament documenté/expliqué pour qu&amp;rsquo;une personne familière avec la ligne de commande et curieuse puisse se faire une idée du fonctionnement du framework.</description></item><item><title>Audi City Christmas 2016</title><link>/portfolio/audi-city/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/audi-city/</guid><description>In 2016, the Audi City store in Paris asked DOUBLE2 and SUPERBIEN to turn its window into a mini advent-calendar. To do so, we equiped the window with a LIDAR and invited people to defrost it to reveal Audi&amp;rsquo;s cars.
As a back-end developer, I was in charge of gathering data from the LIDAR and creating the architecture of the application.
All the pictures below are provided by SUPERBIEN.
You can watch the full report here.</description></item><item><title>Cinema Paradiso 2015</title><link>/portfolio/cinemaparadiso/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/cinemaparadiso/</guid><description>Cinema Paradiso is an event organized by MK2 Group in 2013 and 2015 to &amp;ldquo;celebrate the culture of cinema and entertainment in all its diversity&amp;rdquo;. For both occasions, SUPERBIEN was asked to conceptualize and design the Super Club, turning the Grand Palais of Paris into a night club for one week.
As a backend-developer for SUPERBIEN, I worked on the 2015 edition with Alex Le Guillou to create Michel, a generative VJing software made with vvvv beta.</description></item><item><title>EDF Interactive Wall</title><link>/portfolio/edf-interactive-wall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/edf-interactive-wall/</guid><description>In 2016, SUPERBIEN was asked by AUDITOIRE to create a giant touch senstive wall for EDF&amp;rsquo;s (national electricity company) booth at Viva Tech faire. The constrain for this project was to make the technology as invisible as possible.
As a back-end developer, I was in charge of sourcing the appropriate electronics and laying out the architecture of the application. I also developed some of the mini games that users would play on the wall.</description></item><item><title>Gamma Launcher</title><link>/portfolio/gammalauncher/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/gammalauncher/</guid><description>Gamma Launcher is a small GUI application (patched with vvvv gamma!) that allows you to start a specific vvvv version installed on your system, and add startup options such as -m (allow multiple instances) or --package-repositories (overrides your nugets with those from your development folder).
To get it, simply head over to the release section of the Github repo.</description></item><item><title>LIDAR App</title><link>/portfolio/lidar-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/lidar-app/</guid><description>At SUPERBIEN, I developed a stadalone application (codename LIDARApp) that allows to calibrate multiple SICK 2D LIDARs and perform blob-tracking with them.
To get a glimpse of what the application does, you can have a look at the recording of the 15th vvvv meetup where I made a quick demo of the app.
Right now, the app is being re-written to add more features and update it to the latest versions of vvvv and Elementa.</description></item><item><title>Oceans</title><link>/portfolio/oceans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/oceans/</guid><description>Oceans is a virtual immersive aquarium I worked on with SUPERBIEN for MK2+ and Altarea Cogedim. A total of 11 LIDARs made the 300 meters square video content interactive.
As a backend-developer, I was in charge of creating a standalone application that would allow to easily preview the data gathered by the LIDARs over the network, calibrate it (re-align the LIDARS on a 2D canvas) and perform blob-tracking on that set of data.</description></item><item><title>Out Of Control</title><link>/portfolio/outofcontrol/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/outofcontrol/</guid><description>In 2014, I worked with Visual System on Out Of Control, a sound and light installation in Brussel&amp;rsquo;s Atomium. The installation is based on an original novel by french author Stéphane Beauverger, and explores the relation between human beings and machines, and more specificaly the question of singularity : &amp;ldquo;the inevitable rise of the Super Machine&amp;rdquo;.
On my side, no programming involved this time : I was part of the technical team that set up the installation.</description></item><item><title>Première Pièce</title><link>/portfolio/escapegame/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/escapegame/</guid><description>In 2016, Google created an ephemeral escape game in Paris, named Première Pièce. SUPERBIEN was asked by WE ARE SOCIAL to create video content and interactive experiences for it.
Players had to go through several mini-riddles to finish the game, like searching for items in a high resolution painting that was controlled by their movements, or stepping at the right spot in the room to unlock new clues to carry on.</description></item><item><title>VL.ColorBlender</title><link>/portfolio/vlcolorblender/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/vlcolorblender/</guid><description>This VL plugin wraps the ColorBlender nuget, by Wiesław Šoltés.
Given an input color, it allows you to retrieve a spread of harmonious colors with different algorithms :
ColorMatch 5K Classic ColorExplorer - &amp;ldquo;Sweet Spot Offset&amp;rdquo; Single Hue Complementary Split-Complementary Analogue Triadic Square For each algorithm, you get a process node that takes an RGBA and returns a Spread&amp;lt;RGBA&amp;gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll also find the same nodes as static operations if you enable Advanced nodes.</description></item><item><title>VL.ColorThief</title><link>/portfolio/vlcolorthief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/vlcolorthief/</guid><description>This plugin wraps KSemenenko&amp;rsquo;s ColorThief library in a convenient nodeset. It allows you to extract a color pallette and dominant color from an input image.
Thanks to sebl, the plugin also works with Image and Bitmap inputs.
To install it, simply go to VL&amp;rsquo;s command line and type
nuget install VL.ColorThief Then, go to the help browser and look for Color Thief, you will find two examples :
How to retrieve color palette and dominant colors from an image How to retrieve dominant colors from an image folder For more details, you can check the plugin&amp;rsquo;s repo.</description></item><item><title>VL.DBSCAN</title><link>/portfolio/vldbscan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/vldbscan/</guid><description>VL.DBSCAN allows to use a 2D DBSCAN algorithm in VL. It allows you to identify and track point clusters in a 2D pointcloud.
This plugin simply wraps Stuart Turner&amp;rsquo;s DBSCAN .NET library and provides a few nodes to easily integrate DBSCAN in your projects.
To install the plugin, go to VL&amp;rsquo;s command line and type
nuget install VL.DBSCAN This plugin is one of the building blocks of the LIDAR App.</description></item><item><title>VL.StringExtensions</title><link>/portfolio/vlstringextensions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/vlstringextensions/</guid><description>VL.StringExtensions adds super-useful string manipulation nodes to VL. You can easily do things such as verify if a string is a correctly formatted email address, append a suffix if it&amp;rsquo;s missing, or remove all special characters from a string.
It simply wraps two .NET string extensions libraries :
Jeff Klein&amp;rsquo;s String.Extensions Timothy Mugayi&amp;rsquo;s StringExtensions The plugin also contains simple overview help patches that show all the nodes in action.</description></item></channel></rss>