<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on sebescudie</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on sebescudie</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 12:14:34 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Defcon DFIR 2019 CTF</title><link>/blog/defcon_2019_ctf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/defcon_2019_ctf/</guid><description>Bonjour Ça faisait longtemps! En cherchant un CTF orienté analyse mémoire, je suis tombé sur le CTF DFIR du Defcon 2019. Allons-y donc pour la partie Memory Forensics! J&amp;rsquo;ai choisi cette fois-ci de masquer les réponses.
get your volatility on What is the SHA1 hash of triage.mem?
On nous demande pour commencer de calculer le sha1 du dump mémoire. Et voilà :
┌──(kali㉿kali)-[~/Documents/volatility/2.6] └─$ sha1sum ~/Downloads/Triage-Memory.mem **************************************** /home/kali/Downloads/Triage-Memory.mem pr0file What profile is the most appropriate for this machine?</description></item><item><title>MEMLABS - LAB05</title><link>/blog/memlab_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/memlab_05/</guid><description>Cinquième writeup, cinquième challenge MEMLABS &amp;hellip; allons-y pour l&amp;rsquo;intro :
We received this memory dump from our client recently. Someone accessed his system when he was not there and he found some rather strange files being accessed. Find those files and they might be useful. I quote his exact statement,
The names were not readable. They were composed of alphabets and numbers but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to make out what exactly it was.</description></item><item><title>MEMLABS - LAB04</title><link>/blog/memlab_04/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/memlab_04/</guid><description>Encore un writeup, encore MEMLABS, pour le quatrième challenge cette fois-ci. Commençons par l&amp;rsquo;intro :
My system was recently compromised. The Hacker stole a lot of information but he also deleted a very important file of mine. I have no idea on how to recover it. The only evidence we have, at this point of time is this memory dump. Please help me.
Visiblement, il va falloir rechercher un fichier supprimé &amp;hellip; c&amp;rsquo;est parti !</description></item><item><title>MEMLABS - LAB02</title><link>/blog/memlab_02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/memlab_02/</guid><description>Encore un writeup, cette fois-ci sur le second lab du repo MEMLABS ! Sans plus attendre, la description du challenge :
One of the clients of our company, lost the access to his system due to an unknown error. He is supposedly a very popular &amp;ldquo;environmental&amp;rdquo; activist. As a part of the investigation, he told us that his go to applications are browsers, his password managers etc. We hope that you can dig into this memory dump and find his important stuff and give it back to us.</description></item><item><title>MEMLABS - LAB03</title><link>/blog/memlab_03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/memlab_03/</guid><description>Troisième post, troisième writeup MEMLABS ! Cette fois-ci je vais moins rentrer dans les détails de chaque commande. C&amp;rsquo;est parti pour la description du challenge :
A malicious script encrypted a very secret piece of information I had on my system. Can you recover the information for me please? Note-1: This challenge is composed of only 1 flag. The flag split into 2 parts. Note-2: You&amp;rsquo;ll need the first half of the flag to get the second.</description></item><item><title>MEMLABS - LAB01</title><link>/blog/memlab_01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/memlab_01/</guid><description>Premier article du blog, et c&amp;rsquo;est un writeup ! On va résoudre pas à pas le premier CTF du repo MEMLABS, qui propose de petits CTF centrés sur l&amp;rsquo;analyse de dumps mémoire.
Le but ici n&amp;rsquo;est pas de faire une introduction volatility, mais le writeup devrait être (je l&amp;rsquo;espère !) suffisament documenté/expliqué pour qu&amp;rsquo;une personne familière avec la ligne de commande et curieuse puisse se faire une idée du fonctionnement du framework.</description></item></channel></rss>