<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>installation on sebescudie</title><link>https://sebescudie.github.io/categories/installation/</link><description>Recent content in installation on sebescudie</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sebescudie.github.io/categories/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Audi City christmas 2016</title><link>https://sebescudie.github.io/portfolio/audi-city/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sebescudie.github.io/portfolio/audi-city/</guid><description>In 2016, the Audi City store in Paris asked SUPERBIEN to turn its window into a mini advent-calendar. To do so, we equiped the window with a LIDAR and invited people to defrost it to reveal Audi&amp;rsquo;s cars.
As a back-end developer, I was in charge of gathering data from the LIDAR and creating the architecture of the application. We had to make the LIDAR communicate with the real-time content and schedule the automatic startup and extinction of the application.</description></item><item><title>EDF Interactive Wall</title><link>https://sebescudie.github.io/portfolio/edf-interactive-wall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sebescudie.github.io/portfolio/edf-interactive-wall/</guid><description>In 2016, SUPERBIEN was asked to create a giant touch senstive wall for EDF&amp;rsquo;s (national electricity company) booth at Viva Tech faire. The constrain for this project was to make the technology as invisible as possible. We used some capacitive sensors hidden behind the walls to make specific zones interactive. This project was realy fun to work on since it also introduced lots of physical interactions with the wall.
As a back-end developer, I was in charge of sourcing the appropriate sensors and laying out the architecture of the application.</description></item><item><title>Oceans</title><link>https://sebescudie.github.io/portfolio/oceans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sebescudie.github.io/portfolio/oceans/</guid><description>Ocean is a virtual immersive aqurium I worked on with SUPERBIEN. A total of 11 LIDARs made the 300 meters square video content interactive.
As a backend-developer, I was in charge of creating a standalone application that would allow to easily preview the data gathered by the LIDARs over the network, calibrate it (re-align the LIDARS on a 2D canvas) and perform blob-tracking on that set of data. This eventually gave birth to the LIDAR App on which you&amp;rsquo;ll have more information in a dedicated article.</description></item></channel></rss>